# **Jonas** Margraf

+49 176 57638708 jonasjmargraf@gmail.com jonasmargraf.com LinkedIn | GitHub | SoundCloud: @jonasmargraf

# **READ.ME**

I make sound and art with computers. Coming from a background in music, I'm fascinated by technology and have a meticulous understanding of sonic and visual aesthetics. My passion is to develop immersive experiences and explore technology for creative purposes and commercial applications.

## **SKILLS**

Music Composition
Music Production
Sound Design
Sound Synthesis
Digital Signal Processing

Generative Design

Live Visuals

German (native speaker)

English (fluent)

## **EDUCATION**

**Technische Universität Berlin.** Berlin, Germany. 2015 - Present

M.Sc. in Audio Communication and Technology

Berklee College of Music. Boston, MA. 2010 - 2014 B.M. in Electronic Production and Design (GPA 3.9) Vice President, Berklee Electronica Club

Massachusetts Institute of Technology +

**Berklee College of Music.** Boston, MA. January - May 2014 Sound Installations and Sonic Interventions (Prototype Class)

#### LANGUAGES + ENVIRONMENTS

Ableton Live Max/MSP/Jitter Processing MATLAB Python C

JavaScript + Node.js HTML5 + CSS3 Git + GitHub Raspberry Pi Pro Tools

Adobe Photoshop Adobe Premiere Pro

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Composer, Producer, Sound Engineer, Programmer. 2010 - Present

Freelance. Berlin, Germany

Family Room Specialist. February - June 2015

Apple, Inc. Austin, TX

Concert Producer. February - August 2014

Berklee College of Music. Boston, MA

Experimental Media Designer. January - May 2014

Together Boston, MA

Event Visual Artist. November 2013 - June 2014

HNDMD Music. Boston, MA

#### RECOGNITION

Robert Moog Award Berklee College of Music March 2013

**Achievement Scholarship** Berklee College of Music May 2013

# **SELECTED PERFORMANCES + INSTALLATIONS + PROJECTS**

Arc [Collaboration with Max Joy]. Superbooth 2016. Berlin, Germany [Ambient-Sound-Installation for 24 loudspeakers and software]

Brainwavve - Surface. Austin. TX

[Album, mixed by Audri Acuña and Jonas Margraf]

Applying Psychoacoustics to Key Detection and Root Note Extraction.

Technische Universität Berlin, Germany. 2016

[Paper by Roman B. Gebhardt, Jonas Margraf and Alexander Voß]

**Automatic Classification of Drum Machine Samples Using Artificial** 

Neural Networks. Technische Universität Berlin, Germany. 2016

[Paper by Roman B. Gebhardt and Jonas Margraf]

**Exploded Drawing #28.** The Museum of Human Achievement. Austin, TX [Performance. 2015.]

**Harborwalk Sounds.** *Institute of Contemporary Art.* Boston, MA

[Performance. 2014.]

**Resonating MIT.** Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Boston, MA

[Performance, 2014.]